Bison Hubert

Software engineer with a passion for delivering seamless user experiences and writing modular, efficient, scalable production code. I value collaboration, clear communication, problem solving, and technical growth.

PROJECTS

generocity | https://github.com/bisonhubert/generocity

Generocity addresses the problem of hunger in San Francisco, allowing users to send items from Amazon Pantry directly to donation centers throughout the city. *Technologies:* Ruby/Rails, Javascript, Braintree, Redis, CasperJS, and Bootstrap

Gains | https://github.com/bisonhubert/gains

Gains curates a personalized fitness experience, maximizing results while minimizing the need to research or use wireless data. Workouts are curated based off the previous day's achievements. *Technologies:* React Native, Flexbox, and Realm

Cicadas Mashup | github.com/bisonhubert/mashed-up-cicadas

Inspired by the mix-and-match children's toy, Mashed Up Cicadas creates creepy and hilarious portraits. *Technologies:* Sinatra, JavaScript

EXPERIENCE

Ruby on Rails Developer | MEANS Database

REMOTE | JUNE 2016 - JANUARY 2017

Improve ease of listing donations by integrating image recognition APIs. Verify quality of code with comprehensive unit and integration tests. Convert Rails HTML/SCSS views to React and Flexbox.

QA Software Engineer Intern, Contract | Pillow Homes

SAN FRANCISCO, CA | SEPTEMBER 2016 - JANUARY 2017

Built a framework for regression tests on a native mobile application using ES6, Appium, and Mocha. Created workflow for future tests, as well as documentation for engineering team to add new tests as features are built out. Implemented controller and modules to seed test data.

Front-End Web Developer | UmeWorks, LLC.

REMOTE | MARCH 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2016

Improved site UX/UI with jQuery, CSS3, and JavaScript. Scaled site performance by applying efficient design patterns. Researched frameworks and libraries to achieve client requests.

Oakland, CA (310) 308-3342 www.github.com/bisonhubert www.linkedin.com/in/bisonhubert davidbisonhubert@gmail.com

LANGUAGES & FRAMEWORKS

Ruby/Rails, Javascript, HTML5, CSS3 & SaSS, Flexbox, SQL, Unix, RSpec, Appium, Git

IDEOLOGIES

Agile and test driven development, MVC, objectoriented design, REST

SOFT SKILLS

Pair programming, accelerated learning, effective feedback, EQ, strong written and verbal communication, teamwork, collaboration

EDUCATION

Dev Bootcamp Web Developer Apprenticeship San Francisco, CA June 2015 - October 2015

San Francisco State University Bachelor of Arts, Philosophy San Francisco, CA August 2005 - May 2009 Relevant Coursework: Formal Logic, Philosophical Analysis